harrisinteractive.eu 2018-12-04

# Harris Interactive Europe Group Privacy Policy - United Kingdom

Last updated: 24th May 2018

**Who are we?**

We are Harris Interactive Europe, part of the ITWP Acquisitions Limited worldwide group (“ **We** ” “ **Our** ” “ **Us** ” or “ **Harris** ”). You can see who our group members are by clicking on the link below:  
<http://www.toluna-group.com/en-gb/search-results/contact-us-main>

**Harris Interactive Europe** (comprising Harris Interactive SAS in France, Harris Interactive AG in Germany, and Harris Interactive UK Ltd) is a full service, consultative custom market research agency. Working internationally, our activities span both business-to-business and consumer markets: specialising in; automotive; consumer packaged goods; energy; entertainment; financial services; healthcare; media; technology; telecoms; and travel.

We blend focused sector expertise with award winning research designs and innovative tools and approaches to deliver tailored solutions built on industry best practice. Our engagements range from tactical one-off projects to ongoing strategic tracking studies.

Harris Interactive Europe has in-house expertise covering all areas of research design, implementation, analysis, and reporting, with particular strengths in loyalty, brand and new product development.

The content of this document is presented in the following order:

• Who are we?  
• What is the purpose of this privacy policy and what is our privacy commitment to you?  
• What personal data do we collect about you?  
• How do we collect your personal data?  
• How do we use your personal data?  
• What cookies do we use on our sites?  
• International Transfers.  
• What security measures do we undertake to protect your personal data?  
• What are our data retention and destruction policies?  
• Your legal rights if you are in the EEA  
• What are the legal bases we rely on when processing your personal data?  
• Who is the data controller?  
• Changes to the privacy policy.  
• Privacy contact details

**What is the purpose of this privacy policy and what is our Privacy Commitment to you?**

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy policy aims to give you information on how we collect and process your personal data through your use of our sites [http://www.harris-interactive.com](http://www.harris-interactive.com/), [http://www.harris-interactive.co.uk](http://www.harris-interactive.co.uk/), [http://www.harris-interactive.fr](http://www.harris-interactive.fr/),  [http://www.harris-interactive.de](http://www.harris-interactive.de/), (“sites”) including any data you may provide through this sites when you sign up to our newsletters, purchase a product or service or take part in a competition (our “sites”). It also explains your privacy rights and how laws that are applicable to you may protect you.

These sites are not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.

It is important that you read this privacy policy together with any other privacy policy or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements the other notices and/or policies and is not intended to override them.

**What personal data do we collect about you?**

  * **Information you give us**. This is information about you that you give us by filling in forms on our sites or by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise. It includes information you provide when you register to use our sites, subscribe to our mailing lists, including participating in discussion boards or other social media functions on our sites and when you report a problem with our sites. The information you give us may include your Identity data and your Contact data.
  * **Information we collect about you**. With regard to each of your visits to our sites we will automatically collect the following information: 
    * **Technical data** , including the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, your login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform.
    * **Information about your visit** , including the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL), clickstream to, through and from our sites (including date and time), publications or news you viewed or searched for, page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs) and methods used to browse away from the page.

We also collect, use and share **Aggregated Data** such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does **not** directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific websites feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy policy.

**We do not collect any Special Categories of Personal Data about you.**

**If you fail to provide personal data:** Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.

**Personal data** , means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together follows:

(A) **Identity data** – name (includes first, last, maiden and married names), date of birth, marital status, gender, panellist id and username.  
(B) **Contact data** – postal address, email address and telephone number.  
(C) **Special categories of personal data** – ethnic/racial origin, health, genetics, political opinion, religion, sexual orientation and sex life and biometrics (used for ID purposes).  
(D) **Profile data** – includes your username and password, purchases or orders made by you, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses.  
(E) **Financial data** includes bank account and payment card details.  
(F) **Transaction data** includes details about payments to and from you and other details of products and services you have purchased from us.  
(G) **Technical data** includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this websites.  
(H) **Usage data** includes information about how you use our sites, products and services.  
(I) **Marketing and Communications data** includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences

**Information we receive from other sources**. This is information we receive about you if you use any of the other websites we operate or the other services we provide. We are working closely with third parties (including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers and search information providers).

**How do we collect your personal data?**

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

  * **Direct interactions**. You may give us your Identity data, Contact data and Financial Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you: 
    * apply for our products or services;
    * enter you contact data or Identity data;
    * create an account on our sites;
    * subscribe to our service or publications;
    * request marketing to be sent to you;
    * enter a competition, promotion or survey; or
    * give us some feedback.
  * **Automated technologies or interactions**. As you interact with our sites, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, and other similar technologies. We may also receive Technical Data about you if you visit other websites that deploy our cookies. Please see our cookie policy <http://www.harris-interactive.co.uk/group-cookie-policy/> for further details.
  * **Third parties or publicly available sources**. We may receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources as set out below: 
    * Technical Data from the following parties: 
      * (a) analytics providers such as Google based outside the EU;
      * (b) advertising networks based inside or outside the EU (such as Linked-In); and
      * (c) search information providers inside or outside the EU (Google or Yahoo listing our websites near the tops of the list).
    * Contact data, Financial data and Transaction Data from providers of technical, payment and delivery outside the EU.
    * Identity data and Contact Data from data brokers or aggregators based inside or outside the EU (such as Zoom Info).
    * Identity data and Contact Data from publicly available sources such as Companies House and the Electoral Register based inside the EU.

**How do we use your personal data?**

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.

**Purposes for which we will use your personal data** : We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us by emailing [info-uk@harrisinteractive.co.uk](mailto:info-uk@harrisinteractive.co.uk) if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.

Purpose/Activity| Type of data| Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest  
---|---|---  
To register you as a new customer| (a) Identity   
(b) Contact| Performance of a contract with you  
To process and deliver your order including:  
(a) Manage payments, fees and charges  
(b) Collect and recover money owed to us| (a) Identity   
(b) Contact   
(c) Financial   
(d) Transaction   
(e) Marketing and Communications| (a) Performance of a contract with you   
(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to recover debts due to us)  
To manage our relationship with you which will include:  
(a) Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy  
(b) Asking you to leave a review or take a survey| (a) Identity   
(b) Contact   
(c) Profile   
(d) Marketing and Communications  
| (a) Performance of a contract with you   
(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services)  
  
To enable you to partake in a prize draw, competition or complete a survey| (a) Identity   
(b) Contact   
(c) Profile   
(d) Usage   
(e) Marketing and Communications| (a) Performance of a contract with you   
(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them and grow our business)  
To administer and protect our business and this websites (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data) | (a) Identity  
(b) Contact  
(c) Technical  
| (a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise)  
(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
  
To deliver relevant websites content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you| (a) Identity   
(b) Contact   
(c) Profile   
(d) Usage   
(e) Marketing and Communications   
(f) Technical   
| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
To use data analytics to improve our sites, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences| (a) Technical   
(b) Usage   
| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our sites updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you| (a) Identity   
(b) Contact   
(c) Technical   
(d) Usage   
(e) Profile   
| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business)  
  
**Promotional offers from us:** We may use your Identity data, Contact data, Technical data, Usage data and Profile data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant for you (we call this marketing).

You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us or purchased services from us or if you provided us with your details when you entered a competition or registered for a promotion and, in each case, you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.

**Third-party marketing:** We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any company outside the ITWP group of companies for marketing purposes.

**Opting out:** You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by following the opt-out links on any marketing message sent to you or by emailing us at [info-uk@harrisinteractive.co.uk](mailto:info-uk@harrisinteractive.co.uk) at any time. Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of a product/service purchase, product/service experience or other transactions.

**Change of purpose:** We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us by emailing [info-uk@harrisinteractive.co.uk](mailto:info-uk@harrisinteractive.co.uk).

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

**Disclosures of your personal data:** We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the processing activities table above.

  * Our ITWP group of companies, listed at <http://www.toluna-group.com/en-gb/search-results/contact-us-main> who may be acting as joint controllers or processors and who are based in countries throughout the world, including countries that are not recognised as providing equivalent protection.
  * External third parties based in countries throughout the world, including countries that are not recognised as providing equivalent protection such as; 
    * Service providers acting as processors and who provide us with IT and system administration services.
    * Professional advisers acting as processors or joint controllers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.
    * Tax authorities, regulators and other authorities acting as processors or joint controllers who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances.
    * Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy policy.

We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

**What Cookies do we use on our sites?**

We use site cookies to distinguish you from other users of our sites. This helps us to understand the profile of our visitors, estimate visits to our sites and click throughs for specific campaigns. Cookies also help us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our sites and they also help to improve our sites. These cookies expire when your browsing session ends.

A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we store on your browser or the hard drive of your computer if you agree. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer’s hard drive.

For more information about the cookies we use, please see <http://www.harris-interactive.co.uk/group-cookie-policy/>.

**International transfers**

From time to time your personal data is transferred from a Toluna company that is located in the Europe to a country that has not been recognised as providing equivalent protection. Toluna has put in place transfer agreements using the standard model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries as decreed by the European Commission.

**Toluna USA Inc., – EU-U.S. and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework** : Our global back up and hosting service centre is located in the USA. Toluna USA Inc., ( **“Toluna USA”** ) is a member of the ITWP group of companies and all data we use are transferred to Toluna USA for those purposes. Toluna USA recognises that the EEA (including Switzerland) have established strict protections regarding the handling of personal data from the EEA, including requirements to provide adequate protection for such personal data transferred outside of the EEA. Toluna ensures that it provides adequate protection for certain EEA personal data about individuals (including about you and our corporate clients, suppliers, business partners, job applicants and employees. Toluna USA has therefore elected to self-certify to the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework administered by the US Department of Commerce ( **“Privacy Shield”** ). Toluna USA is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf for the purposes of providing back up services to ensure the security of your personal data. Toluna USA adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement, and Liability. If there is any conflict between the terms of this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.  
For purposes of enforcing compliance with the Privacy Shield, Toluna is subject to the investigatory and enforcement authority of the US Federal Trade Commission. For more information about the Privacy Shield, see the US Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield website located at [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/). To review Toluna’s representation on the Privacy Shield list, see the US Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield self-certification list located at <https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>.

**What security measures do we undertake to protect your personal data?**

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

**What are our data retention and destruction policies?**

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

If you are a citizen or resident of the EEA, or we are processing your personal data in the EEA, in some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see the section entitled _Your legal rights if you are in the EEA_ below for further information.

**Your legal rights if you are in the EEA**

If you are a EEA citizen or resident, you have the right to:

**Request access** to your personal data (commonly known as a “data subject access request”). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

**Request correction** of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.

**Request erasure** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.

**Object to processing** of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.

**Request restriction of processing of your personal data**. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data’s accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.

**Request the transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party**. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.

**Withdraw consent at any time** where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us by emailing to the appropriate email address in the **Privacy Contact** below.

**No fee usually required**

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

**What we may need from you**

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

**Time limit to respond**

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

**What are the legal bases we rely on when using your personal data?**

The law on data protection in the EEA sets out a number of different reasons for which a company that is processing personal data may collect and process such personal data, including:

**Consent** – Generally we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data other than in relation to sending third party direct marketing communications to you via email or text message. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by emailing to the appropriate email address in the **Privacy Contact** below

**Legitimate Interest** means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the best and most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by emailing to the appropriate email address in the Privacy Contact below.

**Performance of Contract** means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract.

**Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation** means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.

**Changes to our privacy policy**

Any changes we make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page, do please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy.

**Privacy contact**

_The Data Protection Officer_  
Harris Interactive Europe  
Ealing Cross  
85 Uxbridge Road  
Ealing  
W5 5TH  
United Kingdom  
Email : [info-uk@harrisinteractive.co.uk](mailto:info-uk@harrisinteractive.co.uk)
